Guide to the Carl Gustav Hempel Papers, 1903-1997 ASP.1999.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Research, Lectures, and Publications, 1918-1992; III.
  - General Lecture Notes, 1935-1992; 3.
    - "Turns in the Evolution of the Problem of Induction," Rudner Memorial Colloquium, 1979 and 1980 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - "Scientific Rationality and Rational Reconstruction," Boston Colloquium 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - "Induction, Valuation, and Rationality in Scientific Inquiry," & Comments by Milic Capek & Errol Harris, Lecture Carleton College, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - "Induktion, Rationalität und Wertung in der wissenschaftlichen Forschung," Lecture Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Symposium Nelson Goodman's Ways of Worldmaking with Published Comments by Hempel, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Notre Dame Lectures and Some Notes, October. 6, 8, 10, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Notre Dame Lectures (Xerox Copy), October 1980 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Workshop on the Literature of Deductivism, University of Pittsburgh, Program, November 1980 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - "Scientific Understanding in the Natural & Social Sciences," Notes on Shanghai Lecture, and 2 issues of Chinese Journal of Dialectics of Nature, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - "Logical Empiricism: Its Problems and Its Changes," Revised Text of China Lecture, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - "The Rationality of Science in Analytic-Empiricist and Pragmatist Perspective," China Lecture Beijing, and Revised Text for Publication in Dialectics of Nature, Undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - "Some Recent Controversies Concerning the Methodology of Science," Peking Lecture, English & Chinese Texts, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Il Simposio Internacional de Filosofia, Oaxaca, Mexico: Correspondence & Ms. of Papers Read, August 1981 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - "Reflections on Theorizing in the Social Sciences," University of Pittsburgh, Department of Economics, November 1982 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Vienna Lecture on Schlick and Neurath, Draft, 1982-1983 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - "Kuhn and Salmon on Rationality and Theory Choice," Boston Paper, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - "Kuhn & Salmon on Rationality and Theory Choice," Typescript of Paper, unpublished, read at APA Meeting Boston, December 1983 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - "Methodology of Science: Descriptive and Prescriptive Facets," Tel Aviv University, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Limits, Provisoes, Jerusalem Paper, Typescript Copies, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Sackler Institute Lecture I & II, Tel Aviv, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Memorial Notes on Ernest Nagel, 1985 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - "Science and Human Values," Kingsborough Community College, May 22, 1986 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - "Evidence & Truth in Science," Locarno 1986 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - "Empiricism: Berlin & Vienna: Materials on the Vienna Circle," incl. letters by Hempel to Albrecht Becker and Hans Reichenbach, 1912-1991 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - "Empiricism: Berlin & Vienna: Materials on the Vienna Circle," incl. letters by Hempel to Albrecht Becker and Hans Reichenbach, 1912-1991 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - "Empiricism: Berlin & Vienna: Materials on the Vienna Circle," incl. letters by Hempel to Albrecht Becker and Hans Reichenbach, 1912-1991 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - "Empiricism: Berlin & Vienna: Materials on the Vienna Circle," incl. letters by Hempel to Albrecht Becker and Hans Reichenbach, 1912-1991 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - "Empiricism: Berlin & Vienna: Materials on the Vienna Circle," incl. letters by Hempel to Albrecht Becker and Hans Reichenbach, 1912-1991 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - "The Significance of the Concept of Truth for the Critical Appraisal of Scientific Theories," Lecture at Rome Conference 'La verità nella scienza', October. 13-14, 1989 & Correspondene with Erspamer, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - "Some Thoughts on Achievement," University of Pittsburgh Lecture, 1989 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - "Reflections about the Empiricist Groups in Berlin and Vienna, ca. 1925-1936," Informal Talk to Princeton Graduate Students, Winter 1989-1990 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - "The Significance of the Concept of Truth for the Critical Appraisal of Scientific Theories," Ms. and Related Comments by Peter Railton, 1990 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Kuhn Conference, MIT, Notes of Hempel's Remarks, Kuhn's PSA Presidential Address, Papers by Others, Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - "Evidence and Truth in Scientific Inquiry", undated (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - "The Irrelevance of the Concept of Truth for the Critical Appraisal of Scientific Claims," undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Lecture Announcements, Posters, and Programs, 1935-1975 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Carus Lectures Notes, 1967-1972; 4.
    - Carus Lectures: Additional Notes, 1967-1969 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Carus Lectures: Additional Notes, 1967-1969 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Materials for Various Chapters, First Outline, Reminder Sheets, Mostly Written 1969(Summer), 1969-1970 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Materials for Various Chapters, First Outline, Reminder Sheets, Mostly Written 1969(Summer), 1969-1970 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Copies of Lecture I and Parts of II and III, 1970 and undated (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Carus Lecture I: "The 'Meaning' of Theoretical Expressions", 1970-1971 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Carus Lecture II: "Theoretical Inference", 1970 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Carus Lecture III: "On the Limits of Theoretical Understanding", 1970 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Carus Ms.: New Notes and Memos, 1970-1972 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Carus Ms.: New Notes and Memos, Carus Lecture I: New Points, 1970-1972 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Carus Ms.: New Notes and Memos, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Carus Lecture Ms., Basis of Lecture Text But More Detailed & with Bibliographic References, undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Carus Lecture Ms., Basis of Lecture Text But More Detailed & with Bibliographic References, undated (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Carus Lecture Ms., Basis of Lecture Text But More Detailed & with Bibliographic References, undated (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Reprints and Articles by Others Used for Carus Ms. and Hempel's Notes, undated (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Carus Ms. Bibliography, undated (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Gavin Davis Young Lectures Notes, 1974-1979; 5.
    - Notes, Reprints for Future Work, 1974-1979 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Lectures 1-3 plus Melbourne Lecture (Combination of Parts 5 & 6), undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Lectures 4-6, undated (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Copies of Lectures 1, 2, 3, and 4, undated (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Writings by Others (according to authors last name), 1935-1991; 6.
    - Achinstein, Peter. "The Pragmatic Character of Explanation," Read at the PSA Meeting, Fall 1985 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Addis, Laird. "On Defending the Covering-Law 'Model'" and Hempel's Response, 1975-1976 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Aomi, Junichi. A Typed Summary in English of His Book Bertrand Russell, 1969 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Bar-Hillel, Yoshua. "Semantic Information and Its Measures," Quarterly Progress Report, Research Laboratory of Electronics, MIT, April 15, 1952 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Behmann, Heinrich. Various Articles, 1935-1937 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Benacerraf, Paul. "Notes on the Incompleteness of Arithmetic" undated, and "Notes on Recursive Functions", 1962 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Berg, Jan. "A Note on Dispositional Concepts", 1956 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Bernays, Paul. "Language, Mathematics and Knowledge," Lecture Given at Princeton University, April 25, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Braybrooke, David. "The Concept of Needs in That One of Its Normative Uses which Is Basic" "Marx on Needs" and "The Reach of the Principle of Preference for Needs", 1979 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Bromberger, Sylvain. "A Theory about the Theory of Theory and about the Theory of Theories," 1963; and Comments on Peter Achinstein's "The Problem of Theoretical Terms," undated (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Brook, Donald. "A Transinstitutional Nonvoluntary Modelling Theory of Art", undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Burks, Arthur W. "Man: Sign, or Algorithm? A Rhetorical Analysis of Peirce's Semiotics", 1978 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Carnap, Rudolf. "The Concept of Degree of Order" and "On the Comparative Concept of Confirmation"; and "Über den semantischen Wahrheitsbegriff", 1937, 1952 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Church, Alonzo. "Schröder's Anticipation of the Simple Theory of Types", 1939 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Coffa, J. Alberto. "Probabilities: Reasonable or True?", undated (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Cummins, Robert. "Functional Analysis", 1975 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Dahms, Hans-Joachim. "Bemerkungen zur Geschichte des Wiener Kreises", undated (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Davidson, Donald. "Hempel on Explaining Action" and "Mental Events", undated (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - De Finetti, Bruno. "Probability: Philosophy and Interpretation" (2 copies), and "Recent Suggestions for the Reconciliation of Theories of Probability", 1963 and undated (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - De Noüy, Lecomte. "Sur l'Unité de Méthode dans les Sciences physiques et biologiques compareés", undated (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Dewey, John. Copies of Excerpts of Dewey's Published Articles and Writings: "The Need for Recovery of Philosophy" Democracy and Education, and "The Supremacy of Method", 1916, 1960, undated (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Diederich, Werner. "Zu Sneeds Theorie der mathematischen Physik--Theorienhierachien und ihre Entwicklung", undated (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - Feigl, Herbert. "Principles and Problems of Theory Construction in Psychology", 1951 (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - Ferguson, Thomas. "The Political Economy of Knowledge and the Changing Politics of Philosophy of Science", 1973 (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - Feynman, Richard P. "The Concept of Probability in Quantum Mechanics", undated (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - Gadol, Eugene T. "Is Incommensurability Among Rival Paradigms a Problem?", 1979 (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - Goldstein, Kurt. "The Task of Biology", 1939 (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - Grandy, Richard E. Review Article on Papers on Foundations of Logic for Journal of Symbolic Logic, 1981 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Grünbaum, Adolf. "Some Reflections on the Intellectual Contributions of German Jewry", 1984 (Box 64, Folder 29)
    - Gruner, Rolf and W.H. Walsh. "The Notion of An Historical Event", 1969 (Box 64, Folder 30)
    - Grunfeld, Joe. Notes Taken at the Third Meeting at Franklin Institute on "Problems of Growth in a Finite World", 1977 (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - Harsanyi, John C. "Rationality, Reasons, Hypothetical Imperatives, and Morality" and "Acceptance of Empirical Statements: A Bayesian Theory without Cognitive Utilities", 1978, 1984 (Box 64, Folder 32)
    - Hattiangadi, J.N. "A Methodology Without Methodological Rules", 1983 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Hellman, Geoffrey. "Logical Truth by Linguistic Convention", 1985 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Janich, Peter. "Newton Ab Omni Naevo Vindicatus", 1983 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Haugeland, John. "Weak Supervenience" undated; and "Semantic Engines: An Introduction to Mind Design" (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Jeffrey, Richard. "Biting the Bayesian Bullet: Zeckhauser's Problem", undated (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Jørgensen, Jørgen. "Empiricism and Unity of Science", 1939 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Kelsen, Hans. "Causality and Retribution", 1939 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Kleene, S.C., and J.B. Rosser. "On Undecidable Propositions of Formal Mathematical Systems: Notes on Lectures by Kurt Gödel, February-May, 1934,"and handwritten Notes, apparently by Hempel (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Kuhn, Thomas S. "Commensurability, Comparability, Communicability," 1982; and "What Are Scientific Revolutions?," Occasional Paper #18, MIT, undated (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Lewin, Kurt, and Karl Korsch. "Mathematical Constructs in Psychology and Sociology", 1939 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Lewis, David. "Statements Partly About Observation," "Mill and Milquetoast," and "Meaning without Use: Reply to Hawthorne, 1987 and 1990 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Majer, Ulrich. "Ramsey's Theory of Mind in Relation to His View on 'Theories'", undated (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Margalit, Edna (Ullman-Margalit). Several Reprints and Related Handwritten Notes by Hempel, 1978-1984 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Martin, Norman M. "Carnap, Rudolf," Encyclopedia Entry, undated (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Massey, Gerald J. "On the Pedagogy of Turing Machines", 1986 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - McMullen, Ernan. "Is There a Philosophy of Nature?", 1969 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Mirabelli, Andre. "Relative Confirmation of Hypotheses," with Author's Cover Letter, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Mundy, Brent. "On Empirical Interpretation," 1988; and Review of The Limitations of Deductivism, ed. By Adolf Grünbaum and W. Salmon, undated (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Nagel, Ernest. Nagel's Remarks on Being Awarded the Butler Gold Medal in 1980 (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - Nagel, Thomas. "Brain Bisection and the Unity of Consciousness", 1971 (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - Neurath, Otto. "The Social Sciences and Unified Science" Copy of Reprint from the Journal of Unified Science [Erkenntnis], and Copies of Excerpt of "Pseudorationalismus der Falsifikation", 1939, undated (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - Neurath, Paul. "Models of the World's Problems and Problems with the World Models", 1977 (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - Nickles, Thomas. "Heuristic Appraisal, Discovery, and Justification: Wither Philosophy of Science?" undated; and "What is a Problem that We May Solve It?", 1980 (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - Nickles, Thomas. "Beyond Divorce: Current Status of the Discovery Debates," "Discovery and Scientific Change," and "Lakatosian Heuristics and Epistemic Support," undated; plus cover letter by author, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Nozick, Robert. "Decemberisions of Principle, Principle of Decemberisions," Draft, September 1991 for Tanner Lectures, Princeton, November 13-15, 1991 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Oppenheim, Felix. "Justification in Ethics: Its Limitations. Comment on Kurt Baier", 1984 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Pearce, David. "Stegmüller on Kuhn and Incommensurability", 1982 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Pera, Marcello. "Proof and Argumentation in Theory-Change. The Galvani-Volta Controversy", undated (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Pfarr, Joachim. "Protophysik der Zeit, ein normatives Fundament physikalischer Zeitmessung?", undated (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Puntel, Bruno Lorenz. "Truth: From Tarski and Correspondence to Coherence, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Quine, W.V. "On the Theory of Logical Types" "A Proof of Church's Theorem" and "Two Dogmas of Empiricism", 1938, 1954, and undated (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Reichenbach, Hans. "On Meaning," Reprint from the Journal of Unified Science [Erkenntnis], 1939 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Resnik, Michael D. Review of Aspects of Scientific Explanation by Hempel, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Rogers, Carl, and B.F. Skinner. "From Family to Society", 1973 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Rudner, Richard S. "Show or Tell: Incoherence Among Symbol Systems" and "Some Essays at Objectivity", 1973, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Salmon, Merrilee H. Review of Rationality and Relativism, Eds. M. Hollis and S. Lukes, 1982 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Salmon, Wesley C. "Consistency, Transitivity, and Inductive Support" and "Introduction: Collected Works of Hans Reichenbach", 1965, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 14a)
    - Scholz, Heinrich. "Die Wissenschaftslehre Bolzanos. Eine Jahrhundertbetrachtung", Winter 1936/1937 (Box 66, Folder 14b)
    - Scriven, Michael. Abstract of D. Phil. Thesis "Explanation of the Supernatural", 1956 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Shapere, Dudley. "The Influence of Knowledge on the Description of Facts", 1976 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Stadler, Friedrich, et al. "Wissenschaftliches Forschungsprojekt: Otto Neurath (1882-1945) - Leben und Werk"; and Information on Exhibition "Otto Neurath und sein Gesellschafts- und Wirtschaftsmuseum in Wien 1925-1934", undated (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Stebbing, L. Susan. "Notes on an Informal Conference on Logical Positivism Held at Belize Park, London, on January 5& 6, 1935 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Stegmüller, Wolfgang. "The Structuralist View: Survey, Recent Developments, and Answers to some Criticisms" undated; and "Der sogenannte Zirkel des Verstehens" (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Stevenson, C.L. "The Nature of Ethical Disagreement", undated (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Suppes, Patrick. "The Study of Scientific Revolutions: Theory and Methodology," and handwritten notes by Hempel, undated (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Vetter, Hermann. "Wahrscheinlichkeit und logischer Spielraum: Eine Untersuchung zur induktiven Logik", 1965 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - White, Morton. "Normative Ethics, Normative Epistemology, and Quine's Holism" and "Good in the Way of Belief," Review of William James: His Life and Thought by Gerald E. Myers, undated, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Worrall, John. "Fresnel, Poisson and the White Spot: The Role of Successful Predictions in the Acceptance of Scientific Theories" and "The Background to the Forefront: A Response to Levi and Shapere", 1984 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Wright, Georg Henrik von. "Wittgenstein on Probability," 1982, copied chapter excerpts from the book Wittgenstein (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Yang, Chen Ning (Frank). "Hermann Weyl's Contribution to Physics" 1990; and "Square Root of Minus One, Complex Phases and Erwin Schrödinger" (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Zahar, Elie. "Feyerabend on Observation and Empirical Content," Review of Der Wissenschaftstheoretische Realismus und die Autorität der Wissenschaften by Paul Feyerabend, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Unknown Author. Unidentified, Incomplete Paper by Unknown Author with Annotation, undated (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Inserts and Notes Found in Books and Index Cards, 7.
    The inserts are arranged alphabetically according to the author of the book in which they were found.
    - A-F (Box 68, Folder 1-7)
    - G-O (Box 69, Folder 1-9)
    - P-Z (Box 70, Folder 1-10)
    - Index Cards with Bibliographic, Subject, and Personal Name Indexes (Box 71)
  - Reviews by C. G. Hempel and Eva Ahrends-Hempel, 1931-1939; 8.
    - Reviews by C. G. Hempel, 1931-1939 (Box 72, Folder 1-4)
    - Reviews by Eva Ahrends-Hempel, 1936 and undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
- Teaching [RESTRICTED], 1937-1985; IV.
  Due to the confidential nature of many documents in this series, users will have to consult with the curator first to see if access can be granted.
  This series comprises a variety of documents relating to Hempel's teaching and educational activities, e.g. course notes, syllabi, exams, and reading lists. In general, Hempel's original folder units were maintained. In cases where Hempel organized his teaching material according to courses, indicated by the course number, several folders for the same course are grouped together and then arranged chronologically within that group. When only one folder exists or the documents do not refer to a specific course, folders are arranged chronologically. In addition, Hempel filed together reprints that he used for teaching. As a result, the teaching material is divided into five subseries. The course notes are comprised in two subseries, one organized according to course number, the other according to chronological order; and the third subseries comprises reprints used for teaching.
  - Teaching Material According to Course Numbers, 1939-1985; 1.
    - Phil 201: Elementary Logic, Course Lectures, Records, Outlines, 1939-1965 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Phil 201: Elementary Logic, Course Lectures, Records, Outlines, 1939-1965 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Phil 201: Elementary Logic, Course Lectures, Records, Outlines, 1939-1965 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Phil 201: Elementary Logic, Course Lectures, Records, Outlines, 1957 and undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Phil 204: Earlier and Later Courses of Same Character, 1947-1961 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Phil 204: Tests, 1956-1959 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Phil 204: Student Correspondence, Comments, and Evaluations, 1959-1973 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Phil 204: Course Records, Suggestions for Changes, 1962-1973 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Phil 204: Tests and Earlier and Later Courses of Same Character (QC, Yale, Harvard, Princeton, Berkeley '75, Carleton '76), 1961-1977 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Phil 204: "Additional Topics: Quantitative vs. Qualitative Approach, A Priori Knowledge, Conventionalist Escape", 1945-1965 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Phil 204: Materials for Science and Morality, Standards of Measurement, Futurology, 1969-1973 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Phil 204: "Lecture Notes for Six Lectures, April 11-27, 1977. Given as Conclusion of The Course Begun by Tom Kuhn" (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Phil 287: Reprints, Photocopies; some used in Phil. 287 Reserve (contains also letter by A. Shimony, Jan. 15, 1982), 1953-1983 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Phil 287: Course Notes up to Fall 1982 and Fall 1984, 1972-1984 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Phil 287: Analytic Empiricist Perspectives on Science in the Light of Recent Criticism, Fall 1976 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Phil 287: Modes & Scope of Scientific Understanding, Fall 1977 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Phil 287: Course Notes, 1977-1984 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Phil 287: Analytic Empiricist vs. Pragmatist Perspectives on Scientific Inquiry, Winter 1978 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Phil 287: Philosophy of Science, Final Exams & Notes, 1978-1984 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Phil 287: Course Records, Syllabus, Exam, Grades, and Student Performance Notes, Winter 1979 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Phil 287: Course Records, Syllabus, Reserve List, Final Exam, Grades, Student Performance, 2 Papers, Winter 1979-1980 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Phil 287: Course Description & Records, Grade Sheet, Reserve List, and Syllabus, Fall 1980, 1980-1981 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Phil 287: Course Description, Course Records, Syllabus, Final Exam, Grade Sheets, Library Reserve, Fall 1982 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Phil 287: Course Records, Syllabus, Exam, Grade & Performance Records, Fall 1984, 1984-1985 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Phil 287: Reprints, Photocopies; some used for Phil. 287 Reserve, undated (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Phil 180: Philosophy of Science, Undgergraduate, Chapter 1-2, Problems of Induction, 1955-1982 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Phil 180: Notes on Psychoanalysis and Scientific Method, Causality, Determinism, Free Will, Operationalism, Science & Valuation (Carleton 1976)(Part I), 1963-1980 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Phil 180: Criteria for Acceptability for Hypothesis & Theories/Marks of Good Hypothesis (Part II), 1973-1982 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Phil 180: Notes on Cause, Law & Explanations; Theories, Objectivity, Value Judgements (Kuhn), Vitalism (Rignano), 1974-1982 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Phil 180: Further Materials Ad Philosophy of Science (Undergraduate), 1970-1976 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Phil 180: Introduction Philosophy of Science, Fall 1976, Fall 1977, plus Kuhn's "Suggested Term Paper Topics" for This Course, 1976-1977 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Phil 180: Philosophy of Science Exams, 1976-1985 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Phil 180: UHP Philosophical Exploration of the Sciences, Fall 1978, Fall 1979, 1978-1980 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Phil 180: UHP Philosophical Exploration of the Sciences, Fall and Winter 1982 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Phil 180: UHP Philosophical Exploration of the Sciences, Winter 1985 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Phil 101: Introduction to Philosophy: Lecture Notes, All Except for Chapter on Ethics, 1965-1966 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Phil 101: Introduction to Philosophy: Lecture Notes, All Except for Chapter on Ethics (part II), 1965-1966 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Phil 101: Introduction to Philosophy, Course Records, Reading Lists, Syllabi, Reference Lists, Exams, 1965-1966 (Box 77, Folder 3)